Jordan Whistler

whistlerjordan@gmail.com https://www.jordanwhistler.info in linkedin.com/in/jordanwhistler

Summary

I am a software engineer based in Eastern North Carolina with experience developing web applications on cloud infrastructure. Recently, I transitioned to the Runtime/ADN team at Netlify and work primarily on CDN proxy and caching software.

Experience

Associate Software Engineer, *Netlify*

03/2022 - present | New Bern

- Enabled local development of edge function geographic and IP data including mocking subregions using the CLI tool
- Contributed code to edge runtime which exposed client IP address for use in edge functions
- · Added detailed audit logging functionality to the Neltify account dashboard for environment variable API events
- Implemented JWT-based edge-side access for web applications served via CDN
- Routinely worked across various ecosystems including GoLang, Ruby on Rails and Javascript/Typescript, Docker/Kubernetes
- Enabled monitoring and alerting using Datadog, Humio, Segment, and feature-flagging with Launch Darkly

Co-Creator, *Able* 07/2021 – 12/2021

- Created Able, an A/B testing framework utilizing Cloudflare Workers and Cloudflare Worker KV for Jamstack applications deployed on Cloudflare
- Developed a Node CLI application to install, set up and deploy services to AWS using AWS SDK/CDK as well as Cloudflare API
- Automated deployment of Umami analytics software supported by AWS services including ECS, RDS, ELB, IAM, and Certificate Manager
- Injected HTML scripts during split testing using Cloudflare HTML Rewriter API
- Automated deployment of worker script to handle splitting of traffic across N variants and serving appropriate static content from Cloudflare CDN while inserting appropriate test cookie and tracking script
- Automated the process of registering TLS certificate and making corresponding DNS entries on Cloudflare nameservers to enable custom subdomain through CLI
- Co-authored Able's case study at www.able-test.com ☑

Skills

GoLang | Javascript (Express, React, Redux, NPM, Handlebars) | Ruby (Sinatra, Rails, Ruby Gems)

HTML/CSS (Semantic HTML) | PostGRES | SQL | MongoDB

Utilities (Git, Github, Linux CLI, HTTP 2, REST API) | Docker | Kubernetes

Education

Software Engineering (Capstone), Launch School

2020 - 2021

A multi-year mastery-based software engineering curriculum

BSBA, International Business Administration,

2002 - 2005 | Columbus, OH

The Ohio State University GPA 3.5

Organizations

US Chess Federation, Youth Chess Coach

2012 - 2014 | Marietta, OH